Dimple Panwar

Software QA Engineer

Contact

Address

Gandhinagar, 382355

Phone

07600949296

E-mail

dimpi8568@gmail.com

LinkedIn

linkedin.com/in/dimplepanwar 44ab7386/

www

https://bold.pro/my/dimplepanwar-230814032233/282

Competencies

Quality improvement plans

Advanced

Root Cause Analysis

Advanced

Risk management

Advanced

Production traceability

Advanced

Test implementation

Advanced

Defect monitoring

Advanced

SR. QA ENGINEER - 8+ years of experience in Organized and dependable candidate successful at managing multiple priorities with a positive attitude. Willingness to take on added responsibilities to meet team goals. Results-oriented QA Engineer polished in developing quality improvement plans and monitoring employee performance to cultivate adherence to company standards. Focused and driven with aptitude for process improvement. Dedicated to going above and beyond to mitigate risk and improve quality.

Work History

2022-01 -Current

QA Engineer

CRED, BANGALORE

- Work in fast paced environment meeting daily deadlines as per end user needs
- Handled test scoping, test strategy documents, creating test cycles, test plans, release cycles, preparing release notes
- Responsible for taking 1:1 with immediate team members for improvement in every aspect
- Conducted detailed discussion with PM, design team, BE, FE and Ops for feature delivery and early failure identification in project
- Use of Charles Proxy to manipulate request/response of APIs
- Prepared documents and reference materials for new joiners and handled training for same
- Responsible for making test process smoother with team growing size
- Tracking of user journey/events via mixpanel for debugging of production issues
- Responsible for taking interviews for new candidates and also run interview drives in different universities and on-sites
- Worked on JIRA, Browser Stack, Postman, Charles, XCode, IntelliJ, Bitbucket, Mixpanel, Linux, Android Studio
- Operated under Agile and Scrum frameworks to complete releases and well organised sprints.
- Gathered data on integration issues and vulnerabilities, reported findings and recommended

Diagnostic reporting Advanced Selenium Advanced Selenium Grid Advanced E2e testing Advanced **Backend Testing** Advanced Integration Testing Advanced System Testing Advanced Mixpanel/Uxcam Advanced Git/Bitbucket Upper intermediate CI/CD Upper intermediate Android Studio Upper intermediate Xcode Upper intermediate Intellij Upper intermediate **Automation Testing** Upper intermediate

System Testing

improvements.

- Responsible for creating notion docs in every release cycle and preparing videos to be uploaded
- Worked on writing, reviewing and execution of Test Cases and Preparation of Test Reports.
- Contributed to root cause analysis to determine core reason for failures and errors.
- Led problem-solving activities to quickly identify and permanently resolve quality and productivity issues.

2017-08 -2022-01

Sr. QA Engineer

Mobiquity Inc, Ahmedabad

- Handled a team of 5 members for different banking projects
- Met deadlines on time and got awarded Best Performer in August
- Worked on writing, reviewing and execution of Test Cases and Preparation of Test Reports
- Testing of Application via API, DB, CRM and UI
- Use of Charles Proxy to manipulate the request/response of the APIs
- Prepared documents and reference materials for new joiners and handled the training for the same
- Events tracking and Zephyr were newly introduced to the team by initiative
- Worked as a part of team of 3 people for Amazon AWS Re:Invent project which was further successfully released all across the world
- Promoted to work in Banking project for BPI and worked as a part of 8 people responsible for performing different kind of functional and non-functional testing for Web and Mobile Application
- Awarded as Best Emerging Player of the year
- Worked on JIRA, test, Postman, Charles, selenium web driver and IDE, Appium during the tenure
- Sole player of the team responsible for handling test cases, test scenarios, performance testing, preparing release notes with Release Manager, providing training to new joiners, performing and creating automation test scripts and handling testing and logging defects and improvements for

Advanced

Platforms : Android/iOS

/WIndows

Advanced

Browser Stack

Advanced

Postman

Advanced

Web Testing

Advanced

Database Testing

Advanced

Blackbox/Whitebox Testing

Advanced

JAVA

Advanced

Maven/TestNG

Advanced

HPQC/JIRA/Zephyr/Qtest

Advanced

Banking/Healthcare

/E-commerce/AWS Domain

Advanced

MS Word/Excel/PP/Sublime

Advanced

Vysor/Quicktime/LiceCAP

Advanced

Agile/Scrum

Advanced

the project

2017-01 -2017-08

Quality Analyst

The Logic Factory, Ahmedabad

- Worked as sole resource for handling company's ERP system and Database Management Testing all across branches of company across world
- Started and completed training for Quintiq which is certification for planning, scheduling and supply chain optimisation
- Worked on JIRA and qtest during tenure
- Worked on SQL Database during span.

2015-10 -2017-01

Software Test Engineer

Stayinfront Pvt. Ltd, Gandhinagar

- Worked as part of pool resource for 6 months responsible for regression testing of Consumer
- Goods and Rx modules for CRM
- Promoted to work as single resource responsible for handling clients like Sugar Australia, L'Oreal, Heinz etc.
- Responsible for direct communication with Project Managers and Leads
- Gained experience in Client Server architecture testing
- Worked on QC 10 and 11 during tenure
- Gained knowledge os all types of testing and completed certification
- Worked on SQL Database during span.

Education

2011-05 -2015-05

Bachelor of Science: Computer Science

Gujarat Technological University - Gandhinagar

- GPA: 8.6/10
- Awarded Top Ranker from the University
- 4 times National Player in Handball
- 3 times University Player in Handball

Certifications

Test Strategy Planning and Documentation

Advanced

Test Scoping Documentation

Advanced

Test Planning

Advanced

LINUX

Languages

Hindi

English

Punjabi

Gujarati

2021-09 ISTQB

2021-09 AWS Certified Cloud

Interests

I enjoy driving cars and spending time with animals in my free time